All my friends are welcome to exercise number 58.
We are asked to write a function that prints that double link, at least consider a double link and
list that we have created in the previous video, and we have a classic note that contains a reference
to the next and the reference for that previous and contains an end date.
So as we have said in the lecture in the previous videos, Lincoln List contains a reference for the
previous and the next notes and contains a box for the date, and we have learned about the function
called Bush now.
We need to allow printing this link at last.
So this doubling in goodness, this is the class inside it.
This is the main.
And this is the function called Bush, OK?
I will create here.
So I will make some
arrangements.
So this is the note.
And I will be this.
These are the methods solved by exercises.
OK.
This we are going to solve in the exercises.
And this is the main for the testing.
OK, so here we are going to test.
OK, now let's think now we need to right in here inside their methods method called Grant for it.
List last week it took interpreting meet better than no note because we are going to refer where is
the first, where is the first node of the list to start from printing the whole list?
This function prints the content of linked lists starting from a given note, and the first and the
given node should be the head of the list to start from printing their lists.
OK, so we start node last equal to no
system
system got out the trend.
End
traversal or printing in four word
way?
OK.
We are going to print in forward and in reverse.
So.
First of all, we start by doing wine.
So wine node does not equal to none.
Then Brent system dot out dot Brent and and no, or I don't need them on every node on there at nine.
So node data plus airspace an empty space.
OK.
Last equal to the node.
And node equal to node dot next, we are moving the cursor, a cursor off the node, the next and jumping
over the notes.
OK, so this loop will go through all the all the nodes inside the list and go and start printing them
at the end system that the print.
System out that like you can make it out with Trent and just end, you know, let's run and see, I
go to the main.
And here
the L L Dot print list and I will start from ahead.
OK, so.
I click on that this green.
Triangle and let's try
and we are expecting nothing printing in forward way one, because we have run this and we have pushed
one.
So we expect only one.
If we remove this that we have created in the previous video, so nothing would happen, we expect no,
no items.
It is empty nest.
So when pushing.
We are adding now I need to create to create again push number two from the previous exercise that we
have created this.
Method.
What do you expect that to be for one or one before to?
Think about it.
Let's go up.
And this is the push adding a note at the beginning of the list.
So we have add that number one and the first and we need to insert two before one because it would be
the last.
Pushing and calling of the method would be the head of that list.
Now let's run and see what our list contains.
And there we go.
Two and one.
So we are adding numbers like here.
So the El Al, if I add like three, it will be pushed at the beginning of their list.
So here we go.
Three do and one and everything is working fine.
OK.
So I will put here three, two and one.
As in order to understand the concept of the next videos, like printing and reversal.
So printing in forward way, I have inserted three, two and one.
One is the top of the list and we need to.
Not to print them by following by for what way.
So here we go three, two and one want to present their head?
OK, now I need from you to write a method that prints that list in a reversal.
So print void print list reverse the reverse.
OK.
It's the same.
So I will.
I am waiting your comments in there and solution in the comments below.
OK.
So before I continue making this so system that out dot print.
Printing that list previously.
OK.
Now, while the last does not equal to none.
What is the last?
We have created a note here called Glasto.
I will create a note called less and less does not equal to no.
This is that this is a pointer for moving and moving with with previously.
So we are going to move backward.
We go to that next.
We are going to the end of the list and we start backward.
OK.
All double anchored list.
All you are going to go forward if you are going to print the list for wordplay.
So the same as above, but different concept and just the last does not equal to null and refer to the
previous and not to the next game.
So here we have a system that outdid print and we have here
printing their list.
Or not printing the article in print
last and or data plus empty spaces.
OK, now let's go down last equal to the last dot.
The brief since we are using and we are going to move backward, we are going to use last thought to
cell and the upper printing and the upper printing forward.
The way we used know Dot next in the reversal where we use, we go to the last and we start last the
previous and we go backward to that list.
So in order to test this, we go to the main method.
Let me go here and I will.
Brent here.
Or I will call the L.L. Dot print list reversely print list for reversely, and I will pass the head
of it.
We start from the hat.
And let's see.
Printing that is at least reversed because here we didn't go back, we go to the head and head, what
is the previous of it?
There's not so nothing would be printing.
There is a trick here.
That we should make a last note.
We need to make here blast equal to the note here, last equal to the note.
So we need to get the last note how to get the last note.
I mean, to create a while to appear that tell me where is their last note?
So no, there's not equal to no.
This will give me that way to find the last note.
So last equal to the no and no doubt equal to the no dot next.
OK, we are looping until finding the last note and the last note equal to the note.
And then we use why Les does not equal to now.
We are going reversely and rolling back.
Let's run and see.
And here we go, guys, we have printing that list in forward, we have at least one two three printing
the list, reversely we have three to and why.
This is the trick behind printing, reversely and printing the less and less.